<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 生物多样性信息学 | 虎克的博客]]></title>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/categories/sheng-wu-duo-yang-xing-xin-xi-xue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-26T21:30:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hooker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[什么是Cybertaxonomy/etaxonomy]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/24/-cybertaxonomy/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/24/-cybertaxonomy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme111.jpg" alt="What is Cybertaxonomy" /></p>

<p><strong>Cybertaxonomy(taxonomy)</strong>: The fusion of taxonomy with cyberinfrastructure will transform descriptive taxonomy, creating a modern, efficient science to confront the biodiversity crisis. <em>Cybertaxonomy</em> will enable international teams of taxon experts, museums and herbaria to create and test taxonomic knowledge to assure humanity’s access to reliable information about earth’s species. The IISE and its partners are forging <em>cybertaxonomy</em> as the next logical link in a chain of scholarship unbroken since the <em>time of Linnaeus</em>.</p>

<p>The challenge is immense: discovering and describing millions of unknown species while at the same time continually critically testing 1.8 million already named species. International “knowledge communities,” each focused on a major taxon, will assemble and continually improve and expand all that is known of our world’s species.</p>

<p>We are conceiving a taxonomy-specific cyberinfrastructure that will become a worldwide “species observatory” capable of opening access to museum specimens, archived literature, collection data, digital instrumentation and colleagues to vastly expedite descriptive taxonomy. Resultant taxon “knowledge banks” will be the 21st century equivalent of revisions and monographs… the “high throughput” species testing mechanisms of the past. Digital tools, instruments and robots can ease constraints on nearly every phase of taxonomy from collecting and preparing specimens to sharing what is known through user-defined portals such as the Encyclopedia of Life (www.eol.org).</p>

<p>Knowing earth’s species and their myriad characters are fundamental to both evolutionary and environmental biology. The costs of building this new taxonomy are insignificant by comparison to the costs of ignorance as we face the biodiversity crisis.</p>

<p>The IISE will focus on four inter-related areas:</p>

<p><strong>(1) Species Inventories and Collection Development; </strong></p>

<p><strong>(2) Revisionary Taxonomy and Monography; </strong></p>

<p><strong>(3) Cyberinfrastructure; and</strong></p>

<p><strong>(4) the History and Philosophy of Taxonomy</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geomapping of Life 我们需要它？]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/23/geomapping-of-life-/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/23/geomapping-of-life-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme12.jpg" alt="COL首页" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Catalogue of Life</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme10.jpg" alt="TOL首页" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Tree of Life</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme11.jpg" alt="CBOL首页" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Barcoding of Life</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme9.jpg" alt="EOL首页" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Encyclopedia of Life</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Geomapping of Life</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[什么是生命科学识别码 LSID]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/21/-lsid/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/21/-lsid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme6.jpg" alt="LSID首页" /></p>

<p><strong>Life Science Identifiers (LSIDs)</strong> are persistent, location-independent, resource identifiers for uniquely naming biologically significant resources including species names, concepts, occurrences, genes or proteins, or data objects that encode information about them. To put it simply, LSIDs are a way to identify and locate pieces of biological information on the web.</p>

<p>The <em>LSID</em> concept introduces a straightforward approach to naming and identifying data resources stored in multiple, distributed data stores in a manner that overcomes the limitations of naming schemes in use today. Almost every public, internal, or department-level data store today has its own way of naming individual data resources, making integration between different data sources a tedious, never-ending chore for informatics developers and researchers.</p>

<p>By defining a simple, common way to identify and access biologically significant data, whether that data is stored in files, relational databases, in applications, or in internal or public data sources, LSID provides a naming standard underpinning for wide-area science and interoperability.</p>

<p>The Life Sciences Identifier is an <a href="http://www.omg.org/">Object Management Group (OMG)</a> Final Adopted Specification developed by the <a href="http://www.omg.org/lsr/">Life Sciences Research (LSR)</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[美国自然科学基金对数字化标本平台的支持]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/20/american-nsfc-bi/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/20/american-nsfc-bi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme7.jpg" alt="项目首页" /></p>

<p>The US National Science Foundation has awarded a <strong>Research Coordination Grant</strong> entitled: <strong>Building a National Community of Natural History Collections</strong>.</p>

<p>The purpose of the RCN is to build a strong scientific community to better serve researchers in systematics, biodiversity, and other fields that use natural history collections.</p>

<p>Three professional organizations, <em>the American Institute of Biological Sciences</em>, <em>the Natural Science Collections Alliance</em>, and <em>the Society for the Preservation of Natural History Collections</em> will provide strong support as partners in the RCN, and many other societies have already built ties with the RCN by appointing Core Participants.</p>

<p>The RCN has the following objectives:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Identify the institutions and people that will define our community and facilitate dialogue among them about how to better serve the needs of researchers,</p></li>
<li><p>identify major opportunities and challenges in the current environment and foreseeable future and develop a strategic plan for the future of collections research,</p></li>
<li><p>determine how to strengthen and modernize the role of collections in education and outreach, and</p></li>
<li><p>identify the primary needs of collections regarding care, curation, storage, and accessibility.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The objectives will be met with a series of workshops, symposia, internships, and a website, <a href="http://www.collectionsweb.org/">www.CollectionsWeb.org</a>, which will provide a forum for interaction, host workshop reports, provide information on ways to become involved in the RCN, and provide links to resources for NHC.</p>

<p>Several major community resources will be developed, including a catalogue of NHC, a survey of the status of NHC, a register of curatorial expertise, and an inventory of innovative and successful educational programs.</p>

<p>Broadening minority participation in collections activities is a goal of the RCN.</p>

<p>The initial steering committee members are Henry L. Bart (Tulane University, vertebrate systematics), Meredith Blackwell (Louisiana State University, fungal systematics), L. Alan Prather (Michigan State University, plant
systematics) and James B. Woolley (Texas A &amp; M University, invertebrate systematics).</p>

<p>Announcements of upcoming events, opportunities to get involved, and reports will be posted to the website, so please check back often. Your input is essential!  Contact us at <a href="http://www.collectionsweb.org/about/steering_committee.html.">http://www.collectionsweb.org/about/steering_committee.html.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[21世纪的物种探险 Species exploration]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/19/21-species-exploration/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/19/21-species-exploration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme8.jpg" alt="Species Exploration首页" /></p>

<p><strong>Taxonomists</strong> discover, describe and classify <em>species</em>. Millions of species remain unknown or unidentifiable, inaccessible to science and society.</p>

<p>Charting the species of the world and their unique attributes are essential parts of understanding the <strong>history of life</strong>.</p>

<p>Reliable taxonomic information is a necessary for managing sustainable ecosystems, attaining conservation goals, and detecting introductions of pests, vectors and invasive species.</p>

<p><strong>Traditional taxonomic tools</strong> and methods have theoretical rigor and rich intellectual content, but are not keeping pace with this growing need for knowledge.</p>

<p><strong>How can we increase the pace at which species exploration progresses while maintaining the scientific rigor of traditional taxonomy?</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
