<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 生物地理学 | 虎克的博客]]></title>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/categories/sheng-wu-di-li-xue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-25T00:42:07+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hooker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[最早的生物地理学地图]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/-/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme999.jpg" alt="最早的生物地理学地图" /></p>

<p><strong>The first biogeographical map</strong></p>

<p>The first biogeographical map was published in the third edition of the Flore franc竌ise by Lamarck and Candolle in 1805, the same year in which Humboldt’s famous Essai sur la Geographie appeared. Lamarck and Candolle’s map marks the beginning of a deive or classificatory biogeography focusing on the study of biota rather than on the distributional pathways of taxa. The map is relevant because it heralds the beginning of the creation of biogeographical maps popularized by zoogeographers in the mid- to late nineteenth century together with the study of biogeographical regions.</p>

<p>see more details on <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1365-2699.2006.01477.x/full">Journal of Biogeography</a></p>

<p>Included file 'JB/setup' not found in _includes directory</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[生物地理学空间单元的分类]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/29/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2009/3/9780521360401.jpg" alt="生物地理学单元" /></p>

<p><strong>Biochore classification and nomenclature in paleobiogeography: an attempt at order</strong></p>

<p>Gerd E.G. Westermann</p>

<p>Abstract: Paleobiogeographic terminology has increased dramatically in recent decades, but the absence of ‘rules’ or even a guide has resulted in confusion and misunderstanding. The Friends of Paleobiogeography are attempting to solve problems related to classification, definition and nomenclature of the biogeographic units (biochores), in conjunction with neobiogeographers. Historic and current developments are discussed. Biochores are highly dynamic units that not only expand and shrink in range, but also change in rank (tier) through time. They should be based on as many higher taxa as possible representing the biota, but from a single major biome, e.g. pelagic versus benthic; different biomes may need distinct sets of biochores. The following tentative ‘rules’ are proposed for a prospective guide for the distinction, ranking and naming of biochores, with emphasis on stability.</p>

<p>Definition: a biochore is defined by the overall endemism of its biota (not particular taxa) within a geographic envelope around a core area, whereas biochore boundaries are defined by the temporary range limits of their constituent endemic taxa.</p>

<p>Ranks (tiers): the biochores ranks are, with ‘bold’ for obligatory use and an additional tentative rank for exceptional conditions in brackets: [Superrealm], Realm, Subrealm, Province, Subprovince; ‘region’ is for informal use. Ranks scale with the degree of endemism as well as duration and biota distribution (range).</p>

<p>A typical region or chorotype and a typical stage (age) or chronotype are designated for each biochore.</p>

<p>Nomenclature: biochore names are geographic and related terms, not taxa-based. Nomenclatural priority begins with Uhlig [Mitt. Geol. Ges. Wien 4 (3) (1911) 229–448]. ‘Rules of Homology’ and ‘Synonymy’ apply in guide form only, e.g. long-term disuse of name or poor definition of biota invalidates synonym or homonym even if senior.</p>

<p>Keywords: biogeography; classification; nomenclature; paleobiogeography; terminology</p>

<p>Included file 'JB/setup' not found in _includes directory</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[保护生物地理学研究进展]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/28/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-28T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2009/3/condore.jpg" alt="保护生物地理学" /></p>

<p><strong>Biogeography: assessment and prospect</strong></p>

<p>There is general agreement among scientists that biodiversity is under assault on a global basis and that species are being lost at a greatly enhanced rate. This article examines the role played by biogeographical science in the emergence of conservation guidance and makes the case for the recognition ofConservation Biogeography as a key subfield of conservation biology delimited as: the application of biogeographical principles, theories, and analyses, being those concerned with the distributional dynamics of taxa individually and collectively, to problems concerning the conservation of biodiversity.</p>

<p>Conservation biogeography thus encompasses both a substantial body of theory and analysis, and some of the most prominent planning works used in conservation. Considerable advances in conservation guidelines have been made over the last few decades by applying biogeographical methods and principles. Herein we provide a critical review focussed on the sensitivity to assumptions inherent in the applications we examine.</p>

<p>In particular, we focus on four inter-related factors:</p>

<p>(i) scale dependency (both spatial and temporal);
(ii) inadequacies in taxonomic and distributional data (the so-called Linnean and Wallacean shortfalls);
(iii) effects of model structure and parameterisation; and
(iv) inadequacies of theory.
These generic problems are illustrated by reference to studies ranging from the application of historical biogeography, through island biogeography, and complementarity analyses to bioclimatic envelope modelling. There is a great deal of uncertainty inherent in predictive analyses in conservation biogeography and this area in particular presents considerable challenges.</p>

<p>Protected area planning works and their resulting map outputs are amongst the most powerful and influential applications within conservation biogeography, and at the global scale are characterised by the production, by a small number of prominent NGOs, of bespoke schemes, which serve both to mobilise funds and channel efforts in a highly targeted fashion. We provide a simple typology of protected area planning works, with particular reference to the global scale, and provide a brief critique of some of their strengths and weaknesses. Finally, we discuss the importance, especially at regional scales, of developing more responsive analyses and models that integrate pattern (the compositionalist approach) and processes (the alist approach) such as range collapse and climate change, again noting the sensitivity of outcomes to starting assumptions. We make the case for the greater engagement of the biogeographical community in a programme of evaluation and refinement of all such schemes to test their robustness and their sensitivity to alternative conservation priorities and goals.</p>

<p>Keywords: Conservation biogeography, models, protected area works, scale, sensitivity analysis, uncertainty.</p>

<p>Included file 'JB/setup' not found in _includes directory</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[企鹅的谱系生物地理学]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/27/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2009/3/35.jpg" alt="谱系地理1" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2009/3/33.jpg" alt="谱系地理1" /></p>

<p>Multiple gene evidence for expansion of extant penguins out of Antarctica due to global cooling.</p>

<p>Classic problems in historical biogeography are <strong>where did penguins originate, and why are such mobile birds restricted to the Southern Hemisphere?</strong></p>

<p>Competing hypotheses posit they arose in tropical–warm temperate waters, species-diverse cool temperate regions, or in Gondwanaland w100 mya when it was further north.</p>

<p>To test these hypotheses we constructed a strongly supported phylogeny of extant penguins from 5851 bp of mitochondrial and nuclear DNA. Using Bayesian inference of ancestral areas we show that an Antarctic origin of extant taxa is highly likely, and that more derived taxa occur in lower latitudes. Molecular dating estimated penguins originated about 71 million years ago in Gondwanaland when it was further south and cooler.</p>

<p>Moreover, extant taxa are inferred to have originated in the Eocene, coincident with the extinction of the larger-bodied fossil taxa as global climate cooled. We hypothesize that, as Antarctica became ice-encrusted, modern penguins expanded via the circumpolar current to oceanic islands within the Antarctic Convergence, and later to the southern continents.</p>

<p>Thus, global cooling has had a major impact on penguin evolution, as it has on vertebrates generally. Penguins only reached cooler tropical waters in the Galapagos about 4 mya, and have not crossed the equatorial thermal barrier.</p>

<p><strong>Keywords: penguins; divergence time; biogeography; nuclear DNA; mitochondrial DNA</strong></p>

<p>Included file 'JB/setup' not found in _includes directory</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[极地植物的长距离散布]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/26/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/2009/3/barringl.gif" alt="LDD" /></p>

<p>由于缺乏对植物物种<strong>长距离散布</strong>频度好的量化估计，我们对它们的分布在气候变化条件下的响应情况的理解受到很大限制。通过分析分布与北极岛屿和Svalbard及其邻近地区的9个有花植物种的超过4000个取样的遗传变异分析，Alsos等的研究表明，自从最后大大冰期以来，在Svalbard岛屿居群的建立过程中，长距离散布的种类来源于多个地区。<strong>因此，长距离散布现象比我们所通常认为的那样要普遍的多，这反过来也表明这些种类分布范围的向北转移可能在全球变暖后发生地相当快速。</strong></p>

<p>Included file 'JB/setup' not found in _includes directory</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
