<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 分类学 | 虎克的博客]]></title>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/categories/fen-lei-xue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-01T01:10:14+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hooker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[植物分类学-比较数据的系统评估第二版]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2012/03/23/taxonomy-stuessy-book/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-23T15:20:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2012/03/23/taxonomy-stuessy-book</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/20120323173901_thumb.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p><strong>Stuessy教授最近又出版了经典分类学著作的第二版。这里有发表在</strong><a href="http://sysbio.oxfordjournals.org/content/59/5/608.full"><strong>系统生物学杂志上的书评</strong></a><strong>和</strong><a href="http://books.google.com.hk/books?id=0bYs8F0Mb9gC&amp;pg=PP31&amp;lpg=PP31&amp;dq=taxonomy+unending+synthesis&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=5PDmIIznED&amp;sig=NDPharGBVmMxVPDDUxnnYxClRrc&amp;hl=zh-CN&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=UxlsT9uuMouQiQe85sjiBQ&amp;ved=0CCwQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;q=taxonomy%20unending%20synthesis&amp;f=false"><strong>Google图书的地址</strong></a><strong>。感兴趣的可以看看。顺便再看看下面的这些报道：</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://news.sciencenet.cn/htmlnews/2009/5/218947.html"><strong>动物分类学》：首师大硕士生以“首师大”命名新物种</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://news.sciencenet.cn/htmlnews/2010/8/235565-1.shtm"><strong>中国分类学急剧萎缩
后继乏人成专家心病</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://news.sciencenet.cn/htmlnews/2009/12/225728.shtm"><strong>分类学研究岌岌可危
中国策划大规模项目拯救濒危学科</strong></a></p>

<h3><a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/325/5936/31.short">China Searches for an 11th-Hour Lifesaver for a Dying Discipline</a></h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[我们还有多少分类学家？]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/10/28/how-many-taxonomists-in-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-28T16:20:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/10/28/how-many-taxonomists-in-the-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>看看这些有意思的文章吧！</strong></p>

<h4>How many taxonomists are there?</h4>

<h4>Essential Reading.</h4>

<p>There is only a limited number of papers and reports that give
information on the status and development of the taxonomic capacities,
especially the human capacities. Our working database with 350
contributions on taxonomy, DNA-Taxonomy, Barcoding and cases studies
will soon be online. The data base include abstracts and links to online
sources.</p>

<p>The whole issue <strong>1444</strong> of volume <strong>359</strong> of the &ldquo;<a href="http://www.journals.royalsoc.ac.uk/app/home/journal.asp?wasp=9744ed2ecce0494487819a5708a4adba&amp;referrer=parent&amp;backto=homemainpublications,4,7;"><strong>Philosophical
Transactions: Biological
Sciences</strong></a>&rdquo;
is devoted to taxonomy and its sattus and development.</p>

<p>Here is an alphabetic listing of what I found (see also the references
there-in):</p>

<p><strong>A</strong></p>

<p>Alberch P (1993) Museums, Collections and Biodiversity Inventories.
Trends in Ecology and Evolution 8(10):372-375.</p>

<p><strong>B</strong></p>

<p>Bisby FA, Shimura J, Ruggiero M, Edwards J, Häuser C (2002) Taxonomy, at
the click of a mouse. Nature 418:367.</p>

<p>Blackwelder RE &amp; Blackwelder RM (1961) Directory of Zoological
Taxonomists of the World. Southern Illionois University Press,
Carbondale, Ill. (No ISBN no. available at that time but Library of
Congress no. 61-15306 )</p>

<p><strong>C</strong></p>

<p>Cribb TH (2004) Living on the edge: parasite taxonomy in Australia.
International Journal for Parasitology 34: (2)117-123.</p>

<p><strong>D</strong></p>

<p>Dickson D (1993) Britain funds taxonomy studies. Nature 362:383.</p>

<p><strong>E</strong></p>

<p>Edwards SR, David GM, Nerlin LI (1985) The Systematics Community.
Association of Systematics Collections c/o Museum of Natural History,
University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kansas 66045. Prepared for the NSF. ISBN
0-942924-12-6</p>

<p><strong>G</strong></p>

<p>Gaston KJ, May RM (1992) Taxonomy of taxonomists. Nature 356:281-283.</p>

<p>Gaston KJ, Mound LA (1993) Taxonomy, hypothesis testing and the
biodiversity crisis. Philosophical Transactions Royal Society, London B
251:139-142. (see link top of page)</p>

<p>Gleich M, Maxeiner D, Miersch M, Nicolay F (2000) Life Counts. 287 pp.
Berlin: Berlin Verlag</p>

<p>Golding SJ, Timberlake J (2003) How Taxonomists Can Bridge the Gap
Between Taxonomy and Conservation Science. Conservation Biology
17(4):1177-1178.</p>

<p>Godfray HCJ (2002) How might more systematics be funded? Antenna
26(1):11-17.</p>

<p>Godfray HCJ, Knapp S (2004) Introduction. Philosophical Transactions:
Biological Sciences 359(1444):559-569. (see link top of page)</p>

<p>Green SV (1998) The taxonomic impediment in orthopteran research and
conservation. Journal of Insect Conservation 2(3-4):151 &ndash; 159.</p>

<p>Groombridge, B (ed) (1992) Global Biodiversity: Status of the Earth&rsquo;s
Living Resources. A Report compiles by the World Conservation Monitoring
Centre. xx, 585 pp.</p>

<p><strong>H</strong></p>

<p>Herbert DG, Smith GF, Hamer ML, Scholtz CH (2001) Taxonomy and
systematics research in South Africa: vital reasearch facing a crisis in
capacity and resources. <a href="http://www.nrf.ac.za/news/docs/sabi_systemsubm.pdf"><strong>Link
&hellip;</strong></a></p>

<p>Holden C (1989) Entomologists wane as insects wax. Science 246:754-756.</p>

<p>Hopkins GW, Freckleton RP (2002) Declines in the numbers of amateur and
professional taxonomists: implications for conservation. Animal
Conservation 5(3):245-249.</p>

<p><strong>House of Lords</strong> Report on taxonomy and systematic biology from
2001-2002: &ldquo;<strong><em><a href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/ld200102/ldselect/ldsctech/118/11801.htm">What on
Earth</a></em></strong>&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>J</strong></p>

<p>Janzen DH (1993) Taxonomy: Universal and essential infrastructure for
development and management of tropical wildlands biodiversity.
Proceedings of the Norway/UNEP Expert Conference on Biodiversity, O.T.
Sandlund and P. J. Schei (eds.), Trondheim, May, 1993. NINA, Trondheim.
100-113.</p>

<p><strong>K</strong></p>

<p>Klopper RR, Smith GF, Chikuni AC (2001) The Global Taxonomy Initiative:
documenting the biodiversity of Africa. Strelitzia 12:xiii, 1-203.</p>

<p>Konsortium Systematics Agenda 2000 (1996) Agenda Systematik 2000. Kleine
Senckenberg Reihe 21. 55 pp.</p>

<p>Kraus O (1976) Zoological Systematics in Central Europe (Zoologischer
Systematik in Mitteleuropa). sonderbände des Naturwissenschaftlichen
Vereins in Hamburg 1. Verlag Paul Parey, Hamburg und Berlin. ISSN
0301-2697. ASTM-Coden: AVNHAV.</p>

<p>Krell FT (2000) Impact factors aren&rsquo;t relevant to taxonomy. Nature
405:507-508.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong></p>

<p>May RM (1990) Taxonomy as destiny. Nature 347:129-130.</p>

<p>May RM (1990) How many species? Philosophical Transactions of the Royal
Society B 330:293-304. (see link top of page)</p>

<p>Marioni L, Magalhães C &amp; Marques AC (2005?) <a href="http://www.cria.org.br/cgee/documentos/docgeralzool.doc">PROPOSTAS DE ESTRATÉGIAS E
AÇÕES PARA A CONSOLIDAÇÃO DAS COLEÇÕES ZOOLÓGICAS
BRASILEIRAS</a>.
(In Portugese, DOC download, 300 KB)</p>

<p>Marques AC &amp; Lamas CJE (2005?) <a href="http://www.cria.org.br/cgee/junho/docs/EstadoArteZoologia.pdf">Sistemática zoológica no Brasil: estado
da arte, expectativas e sugestões de ações
futuras</a>
(48 pp, PDF download, 330 KB). In Portugese.</p>

<p><strong>N</strong></p>

<p>National Science Foundation NSF (2004) Workshop to Produce a Decadal
Vision for Taxonomy and Natural History Collections. <a href="http://www.flmnh.ufl.edu/linne/NSF_Workshop_Report_3-08-04.pdf">Link
&hellip;</a></p>

<p>PRELIMINARY REPORT OF FIRST GLOBAL TAXONOMY INITIATIVE WORKSHOP IN ASIA.
<a href="http://www.gti-kontakstelle.de/toolkit/toolkit1/SBSTTA-09-rec-en.pdf">UNEP/CBD/SBSTTA/9/INF/17</a>.
12 September 2003.</p>

<p><strong>S</strong></p>

<p>Samper C (2004) Taxonomy and environmental policy. Philosophical
Transactions: Biological Sciences 359(1444):721–728. (see link top of
page)</p>

<p>Schminke HK (1996) Naturkundliche Sammlungen &ndash; Das vernachlässigte Erbe?
Spektrum der Wissenschaft 1996:116-119.</p>

<p>Schminke HK (1994) Wiederaufbau von Forschung und Lehre in der
Zoosystematik &ndash; Eine nationale Aufgabe. Spektrum der Wissenschaft
1994(September):114-116.</p>

<p>Simonetti JA (1997) Biodiversity and a taxonomy of Chilean taxonomists.
Biodiversity and Conservation 6(4):633 &ndash; 637.</p>

<p>Suarez AV, Tsutsui ND (2004) The Value of Museum Collections for
Research and Society. BioScience 54(1):66-74.</p>

<p>Systematics Agenda 2000 (1994) Charting the Biosphere. Systematics
Agenda 2000.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong></p>

<p>Wägele JW et al (200X) Methoden, Aufgaben und Leistungsfähigkeit der
modernen Systematik. Kleine Senckenberg Reihe 36:40 pp.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<strong><em><a href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/ld200102/ldselect/ldsctech/118/11801.htm">What on
Earth</a></em></strong>&rdquo;
the House of Lords Report on taxonomy and systematic biology from
2001-2002.</p>

<p>Williams J et al (2001) Biodiversity Theme Report. Australia State of
the Environment Report 2001 (Theme Report). ISBN 0 643 06749 3; <a href="http://www.deh.gov.au/soe/2001/biodiversity/index.html">Link
&hellip;</a></p>

<p>Winston JE, Metzger KL (1998) Trends in taxonomy revealed by the
published literature. BioScience 48:344-346 or 125-128.</p>

<p><strong>Z</strong></p>

<p>Ziegler W et al (1997) Biodiversitätsforschung: Ihre Bedeutung für
Wissenschaft, Anwendung und Ausbildung. Kleine Senckenberg Reihe
26:1-68.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>来自：<a href="http://www.gti-kontaktstelle.de/taxonomy_Lit.html" title="http://www.gti-kontaktstelle.de/taxonomy_Lit.html">http://www.gti-kontaktstelle.de/taxonomy_Lit.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[当达尔文遇见Facebook:社会化的网络工具让自然博物学家们可以分享数据]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/10/14/when-darwin-meet-facebook/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-14T12:30:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/10/14/when-darwin-meet-facebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>自然历史学家希望能够将地球上的生命多样性进行详细的刻画。然而，这门学科却遭遇大量研究信息和数据没有被充分利用的尴尬局面。英国大英自然历史博物馆的研究人员设计了出了一个叫“<a href="http://scratchpads.eu/">Scratchpads</a>”的工具是科学家们可以相互分享他们的研究成果。</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.cnpc.ac.cn/images/image_8.png"><img src="http://blog.cnpc.ac.cn/images/image_thumb_8.png" title="image" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>Scratchpads基于开源的内容管理<a href="http://drupal.org/">Drupal</a>基础上的二次开发。因此该系统除了具备Drupal本书的博客、合作编辑、论坛、网络社区、新闻通告、图片管理、数据上传和下载等基本的功能。大英自然历史博物馆的科学家在此基础上开发除了一些针对分类学家使用的模块，比如生物标本和文献，分类树数据的导入和导出，以及通过WebService技术是用户可以非常方便的使用<a href="http://scholar.google.com/">Google
Scholar</a>, <a href="http://www.biodiversitylibrary.org/">Biodiversity Heritage
Library</a>,
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/">flickr</a>, <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Genbank/index.html">NCBI
Genbank</a>,
<a href="http://www.morphbank.net">Morphbank</a>等网站的相关信息.</p>

<p>原文地址：<a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/11/091110065917.htm" title="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/11/091110065917.htm">http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/11/091110065917.htm</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[植物名录相关术语]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/05/19/terms-in-plants-chekclist/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-19T12:30:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2011/05/19/terms-in-plants-chekclist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Native, Invasive, and Other Plant-Related Definitions</h1>

<h5>Native Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A plant that is a part of the balance of nature that has developed
over hundreds or thousands of years in a particular region or
ecosystem. Note: The word native should always be used with a
geographic qualifier (that is, native to New England [for example]).
Only plants found in this country before European settlement are
considered to be native to the United States.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Invasive Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A plant that is both non-native and able to establish on many sites,
grow quickly, and spread to the point of disrupting plant communities
or ecosystems. Note: From the Presidential Executive Order 13112
(February 1999): &lsquo;An invasive species is defined as a species that is
1) non-native (or alien) to the ecosystem under consideration and 2)
whose introduction causes or is likely to cause economic or
environmental harm or harm to human health.&rsquo; In contrast to item 2) of
the Executive Order, which includes plants invasive in agricultural
settings, the Connecticut Invasive Plant Working Group lists
non-native plants as invasive only if they invade minimally managed
(natural) areas.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Non-Native Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A plant introduced with human help (intentionally or accidentally) to
a new place or new type of habitat where it was not previously found.
Note: Not all non-native plants are invasive. In fact, when many
non-native plants are introduced to new places, they cannot reproduce
or spread readily without continued human help (for example, many
ornamental plants).</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<h5>Naturalized Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A non-native plant that does not need human help to reproduce and
maintain itself over time in an area where it is not native. Notes:
Even though their offspring reproduce and spread naturally (without
human help), naturalized plants do not, over time, become native
members of the local plant community. Many naturalized plants are
found primarily near human-dominated areas; and, sometimes,
naturalized is used (confusingly) to refer specifically to naturally
reproducing, non-native plants that do not invade areas dominated by
native vegetation. However, since invasive plants also reproduce and
spread without human help, they also are naturalized – invasives are a
small, but troublesome, sub-category of naturalized plants.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Exotic Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A plant not native to the continent on which it is now found. (Plants
from Europe are exotic in North America; plants from North America are
exotic in Japan.)</p></blockquote>

<h5>Translocated Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A plant not native to the portion of the continent where it is now
found. (California Poppies in New England are an example of a
translocated species.)</p></blockquote>

<h5>Opportunistic Native Plant</h5>

<blockquote><p>A native plant that is able to take advantage of disturbance to the
soil or existing vegetation to spread quickly and out-compete the
other plants on the disturbed site.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Weed</h5>

<blockquote><p>Common Usage &ndash; A weed is a plant (native or non-native) that is not
valued in the place where it is growing (USDA Animal and Plant Health
Inspection Service (APHIS)). Definition****&ndash; Any plant that poses a
major threat to agriculture and/or natural ecosystems within the
United States.</p></blockquote>

<h5>Noxious Weed</h5>

<blockquote><p>Common Usage &ndash; A plant that is particularly troublesome. Legal Context
(Federal Plant Protection Act) &ndash; Any plant or plant product that can
directly or indirectly injure or cause damage to crops (including
nursery stock or plant products), livestock, poultry or other
interests of agriculture, irrigation, navigation, the natural
resources of the United States, the public health, or the environment.
<em>Note: USDA APHIS maintains a list of federally-recognized noxious
weeds. It is illegal to import Federally listed noxious weeds or
transport them across state lines. Some states or counties maintain
lists and have passed laws regarding responsibilities for their
control (not applicable in Connecticut). Connecticut laws ban the sale
or transport of noxious weed seeds.</em></p>

<h3>参考文献:Naturalization and invasion of alien plants: concepts and definitions {style=&ldquo;text-align: left;&rdquo;}</h3>

<p>这里下载<a href="/files/2011/5/A-00249.pdf">A-00249.pdf (404.69 kb)</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[分类学是生物多样性研究的基础]]></title>
    <link href="http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/taxonomy-for-biodiversity/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Apiaceae.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/taxonomy-for-biodiversity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2009/3/vtheme4.jpg" alt="分类学和生物多样性" /></p>

<p><strong>Biodiversity Update–Progress in Taxonomy</strong></p>

<p>Taxonomy and systematic biology responded to the “biodiversity crisis” and the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) by defining three major challenges: completing the inventory of life, discovering evolutionary relationships through phylogenetic analysis, and providing information via the Internet (2). Progress in reconstructing the “Tree of Life” (3, 4) is effective and well coordinated, with phylogenetics increasingly integrated into ecology, biogeography, and developmental biology (5).</p>

<p>However, we are far from placing each species in its phylogenetic context, because the inventory itself lags behind. Out of a minimum of 4 million species, about 1.7 million (6) have so far been recognized through comparative studies of preserved specimens in reference collections. Information technology can accelerate this work (7), but the core of the discipline will remain. Specimens will be needed to confer repeatability on the hypothesis that a particular element of biodiversity constitutes a species and for taxonomists to identify new species and unfamiliar organisms.</p>

<p>As the World Conference on Sustainable Development (8) convenes, do we know enough either to conserve biodiversity or to make the best use of it? The Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF) is a vital step toward accessible species-level information (9, 10). It establishes an informatic architecture for synthesizing knowledge, capable of uniting taxonomic initiatives such as Species 2000 (11) with regional databases (12, 13). If information that exists only in biological collections can also be computerized, users everywhere will share the benefits (14). Retrospective digitization of collections requires most investment, after which data capture and stewardship can be linked to ongoing curatorial work. Access to images of the type specimens that define species is one of the highest priorities, and the All Species Foundation’s proposal to digitize 50% of them in 5 years (15) poses no technical challenges once funding is secured. Surprisingly, digitizing collections is a contentious topic where the priorities of conservationists and taxonomists differ. The former tend to favor biodiversity conservation databases (16) based on field observations of the status of species. The latter recognize the importance of such efforts that build on the traditions of biological recording but point out that they are only practicable for groups where taxonomic work has progressed to provide detailed species level information.</p>

<p>Otherwise, what can be observed and recorded? This, together with the availability of skillful amateurs equipped with excellent field guides, is why birds are useful indicators of trends in biodiversity, but microalgae, although suitably widespread, abundant, and sensitive to change, are not. Historical data from collections already play a powerful role in planning and development in Mexico (17) and could do so universally. Biological collections may represent an inadequate sample of past and present biota, but they are the only identified and authenticated sample we have. Biological recording and collections are complementary, not competing, sources of knowledge about the world, with the latter enabling repeatable observations and entirely new kinds of investigation. Prospects are not good for the first and most fundamental challenge: a global inventory of life on Earth.</p>

<p>E.O.Wilson diagnosed the problem as the limited capacity of collections institutions and the shortage of taxonomists (18), conclusions shared by a recent UK review (19). Wilson estimated the cost at around $5 billion, about the same as the Human Genome Project. Success would require increased taxonomic capacity, in terms of people and collections, around the world. These are the goals of the Global Taxonomy Initiative (20), for which developing countries can receive resources from the Global Environment Facility (GEF) (21).</p>

<p>The All Species Foundation also aspires to complete the global inventory within “a single human generation” but focuses on developing sources of private funding. Redirection of existing resources might be more effective. Developed countries mainly contribute to the international objectives of the CBD through the GEF, which has so far committed $3.86 billion to biodiversity projects, especially in protected areas. They might achieve more by targeting a significant proportion of the resources that go to the GEF directly to their own taxonomic institutions, enabling them to reap the benefits of the long-term investment that created them. There can be little doubt that such resources could be deployed rapidly and effectively. The National Science Foundation has shown how quickly taxonomic expertise can be generated even in groups where it was scarce (22). Strategic plans, and the networks to implement them, have been established in many regions (23-25) with a few countries alrea***mitted to national inventories (26, 27). The documentation of life on Earth, on which our own well-being ultimately depends, surely deserves to be among our most urgent priorities for investment.</p>

<p><strong>Science 11 October 2002: Vol. 298. no. 5592, p. 365 DOI: 10.1126/science.1075026</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
